# Anomitra Saha

Permanent Address: 55, Rafi Ahmed Kidwai Road, Kolkata - 700055

**Phone:** +91-8981728476

Email: anomitra.s@gmail.com

### **Summary**

I am a backend developer with three years of experience. Over the last couple of years, I have been building backend APIs for RESTful backend web applications. I'm experienced in API design and definition, high-level system design and implementation. I am comfortable with Python and Java, and have previously worked on Spring, Django and other web frameworks.

Designing software solutions that work at scale has always been a passion for me, and I'm looking for a role which gives me the opportunity to do the same.

### **Experience**

### Software Development Engineer II at Livspace

2019 - Present

- As a part of the **Catalog Management** team, I am involved in the design and development of software which makes our inventory of around **40+ lakhs** of structured and unstructured items accessible to the design partners and other business stakeholders.
- For our **Business Analytics** team, I built and still continue to maintain some periodic data sync tools. These tools create **fact tables** which serve as the basis for our business intelligence reports.

#### Computer Scientist at Belzabar Software Design

2016 - 2018

- ■ Primarily involved in designing and implementing **RESTful** backend APIs for multiple web applications.
- As a member of the backend team, I worked with the **New York State DMV** to build a **Django** web app which enables auto dealers to perform all vehicle registrations and transfer activities online, on a web application. I had considerable input over the **API design** and definition of this project.

#### Education

#### B.Tech in Information Technology from NIT Durgapur

2012 - 2016

Learnt about core computer science concepts, software engineering and development. Worked on several research projects during this time, and was a leading member of the **GNU/Linux Users' Group**, where we tried to popularise the use of open source software across the campus. Graduated with **distinction**, having a CGPA of **8.21**.

## **Personal Projects**

### Research Project at IIT Kharagpur

Worked on a project which solved the **shortest path problem** in Graph Theory. The goal was to design an algorithm to find the shortest possible path(s) in a multi-attribute graph. I designed and implemented the algorithm, which was then used in the Department of Architecture, IIT Kharagpur to work on real world data sets.

## **Skills**

**Programming Languages:** Python, Java, Ruby

Web Technologies: Spring, Django, Django REST Framework, Ruby On Rails, Spring MVC

Developer Tools: Docker, AWS ecosystem, Gitlab CI, Jenkins CI, Celery Task Scheduler

**Software Engineering:** Agile, Design Patterns, Test Driven Development, SOLID principles